http://www.sporthouse.ie/pages/privacy-policy

Privacy policy
Your privacy is important to us
1. General
This Privacy Policy sets out how Sporthouse ltd will store and use information relating to you, and applies to the entire website www.sporthouse.ie ("Website"). Sporthouse is a trading name of Sporthouse ltd ("we", "our", "us").
We may update and change our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any significant changes but recommend you come back and check this Privacy Policy whenever you wish.
2. What we collect
Sporthouse is committed to protecting your privacy. Where you provide us with any information by which you can be identified, then we will only use it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
We collect the information that you provide to us via the Website, which may include the following:
where you order products, we will collect your name, contact details and billing information, transaction and credit card information.
when you visit our Website, we may record the URL you came from, IP address, domain types like .ie and .com, your browser type, the country where your computer is located, the pages of our website that were viewed during your visit, and any search terms that you entered on our website.
when you register with us to receive our e-mails or details of offers or products we will collect your e-mail address;
we may ask you to provide us with information about you and your family so that the details of offers and products we send you will be more suited to your circumstances; and
when you visit our Website, we use cookies, which are programs which collect additional information. In order to learn more, see how we use cookies below.
3. How is your personal data collected?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including:
Direct interactions. You may give us your identity, contact details and other data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by email, phone or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
buy our products or services;
request marketing to be sent to you;
enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
give us feedback.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our Website, we may automatically collect technical data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies.
Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services.
What do we do with the information we gather?
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
internal record keeping.
processing your orders.
to analyse the use of the Website, for example: when you visit our Website we may record when & how you interact with our Website. This information is retained and used to note your interest in our Website, improve customer journeys and personalise your experience where possible
we may use the information to improve our products and services.
to contact you about leaving a review on a product once your order has been completed. If you do not wish to be contacted for this purpose, please click the unsubscribe button you will find on the review email.
If we have your consent, we will send you promotional e-mail about new products, special offers and services or other information from Sporthouse (unless you have asked us not to do so and/or where you update your marketing and communication preferences).
your personal information may be disclosed to selected third party companies which will help us to process your order, to comply with our obligations, to manage and store data, to run our marketing campaigns and/or provide data analytics. These third parties will never contact you for marketing purposes and will only use the data in accordance with our instructions.
We will use the personal information we hold about you (as well as pseudonymised or anonymised information generated from your personal information) to carry out analysis and research, including:
data analytics, whereby we combine information (such as personal information we have obtained through the use of the Website or from your browsing history):
to learn more about our customers and their preferences;
to identify patterns and trends amongst our customers;
provide information, content and offerings tailored to our customers' needs;
develop new products and services;
monitor performance of our products and services and/or improve our technology;
to be able to send you personalised marketing messages; and
to display online ads to you.
When you use the Website and have not advised us to the contrary, you are agreeing that we may use your personal information for the purposes set out in this statement.
5. Competitions
We regularly run competitions and prize draws and, in addition to your answer or entry, we will require you to send us certain information, such as your name and email address. We will only use this information to administer the competition prize and for any other purpose to which you consented when you entered. If any Competition also needs other personal data to be provided about you, this will be made clear by the entry fields you need to complete to enter into the Competition. If you are a winner, we may also collect additional personal data from you that you provide to us to enable us to make any prize available to you.
6. International transfers of your personal data
Unless stated otherwise, we store and process your personal information in the European Union. There will, however, be occasions when we need to transfer your personal information outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA") to a country which does not provide the same level of data protection as the country in which you normally use our products and/or services. In these circumstances we will take appropriate steps to ensure that your personal information is adequately protected.
7. Online media channels
We may use information from online media sources such as websites, social media and information sharing platforms. This information may be used to help tailor and improve our services and communicate with you effectively. Where we use information from these sources, we will respect any permissions you have set about how you would like your information to be used. We recommend you routinely review the privacy notices and preference settings that are available to you on any online media channels, so these can be followed.
8. Your rights
Right to access to your personal data: you have the right to obtain information as to whether or not your personal data is being processed, and, where that is the case, access to it. To access your personal data, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
Right to rectification: you have the right to rectify inaccurate personal data concerning you. To request any rectification of your personal data, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
Right to erasure: you have the right to request erasure of your personal data. To request erasure of your personal data, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
Right to restriction of processing: you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data, when you indicate that the data is inaccurate, or where you have requested the deletion of your data or when you have objected to the processing of your data. To request restriction of the processing of your personal data, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
Right to data portability: you have the right to receive your personal data, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to ask us to transmit that data to another controller. To request portability of your data, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
Right to object: where we process your data based on our legitimate interest to do so, or when processed for marketing purposes, you have the right to object. To object, please contact us at info@sportshouse.ie
9. What we may need from you
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
10. Data security
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
11. Data retention
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
12. Our cookies policy
What are cookies?Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by the websites that you visit. They make your online interactions faster and easier.
On this website we use two types of cookies:Session Cookies: These are temporary cookies which are stored during your browsing session. They are automatically deleted from your computer or device when you close your browser.
Some of the things we use session cookies for include:
allowing you to move from page to page on our website
remembering what you have in your shopping basket
allowing us to take payment for and complete your order
Persistent Cookies: These are cookies which are not deleted from your computer or device after you have visited our website. These cookies help us to remember you and your preferences when you come back to this website.
Some of the things we use persistent cookies for include:
remembering your journey around our website
remembering your preferences when you come back to our website
allowing you to interface with social media sites
13. Cookies we use
The table below contains details of the cookies we use and why. The data we collect and record via cookies are completely anonymous. The data will never contain any of your personal details.
14. How do I manage cookies?
Most web browsers allow you to control cookies through your browser settings.If your web browser is not detailed above or you are using a mobile device, please consult your user manual or online help guide for details on how to control cookies. To find out more about cookies and how to manage them, you may wish to visit www.allaboutcookies.org.Please remember that all of the links above are third party websites. We do not endorse them and are not responsible for their contents.
What happens if I disable cookies?
If you disable cookies it may affect the service you receive from our website. For example you may not be able to:
view images
add items to your basket or buy them
Please remember that if you wish to disable cookies you will need to do this each time you visit our website.
15. Contact us
If you have any questions about our cookies policy please contact:info@sportshouse.ie
Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Nam fringilla augue nec est tristique auctor. Donec non est at libero.
Share this product
